<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<root>
	<article id="1">
		<title>Javascript bitwise operators and how to use them</title>
		<createdAt>04/14/2017</createdAt>
		<keywords>javascript; bitwise operators;</keywords>
		<description>The majority of javascript developers knows about bitwise operators and binary representations of numbers. However if you asked them where in web development we can use those operators you rarely hear a clear answer. So was I until I started to use bitwise operators in one  project where we had to grant and control different user roles on the webportal.</description>
		<src>bitwiseOpers.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="2">
		<title>Contact form with PHP mail() and SMTP authentication</title>
		<createdAt>05/12/2017</createdAt>
		<keywords>javascript; PHP; SMTP; mail; contact form;</keywords>
		<description>When you developing web sites in most cases you facing up with necessity to create 'contact us' form. No matter if it is a simple landing page for a small business, portfolio web site or a huge web platform, everyone wants to communicate, leave a feedback, ask question or whatever. Whereas some popular CMS platforms provide developers with different mailing addons, you might need something simple with possibility to customize it. Here is my simple 'contact us' form with HTML and PHP.</description>
		<src>contactFormWithPhp.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="3">
		<title>Sublime and Emmet. Increase your development speed</title>
		<createdAt>05/22/2017</createdAt>
		<keywords>sublime; emmet; zen coding; html; improve process</keywords>
		<description>Today I'm going to tell few words about one of my favorite editors Sublime text. It's very light, easy to use, provides many interesting user settings like changing color schemes or fonts, and the most important - it has plenty of usefull plugins, that helps to improve the speed and quality of the development.</description>
		<src>sublimeAndEmmet.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="4">
		<title>Hiring process in Silicon Valley</title>
		<createdAt>07/24/2017</createdAt>
		<keywords>hiring; interview; </keywords>
		<description>Recently I finished my long way to a dream job in America. I have attended lots of interviews in different companies at Silicon valley,
		so I have enough experience to share with those who are moved here from another country and not familiar with the american hiring process.</description>
		<src>interviews.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="5">
		<title>Implement google cloud functions with Firebase</title>
		<createdAt>09/06/2017</createdAt>
		<keywords>google cloud; firebase; </keywords>
		<description>I've been playing with Google Cloud Functions for a couple of weeks and actually host
			one working business web application on the Firebase. While I found gcloud functions easy to write and deploy, there is still no clean and short tutorial on how
			you can create and start using cloud functions. Below is a short tutorial with some upcoming issues and fixes. </description>
		<src>cloudFunc.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="6">
		<title>Deploy Meteor app on AWS from scratch</title>
		<createdAt>06/10/2018</createdAt>
		<keywords>aws; meteor; </keywords>
		<description>Meteor a platform for building web apps on pure JS becomes more and more popular.
      I spent some time deploying my recent Meteor project on AWS and I found this
      experience a little confusing and time-consuming. So here is a steps to set up
      everything from scratch. Hope this manual will help to save time and to
      avoid most common issues. </description>
		<src>deployMeteorOnAmazon.html</src>
	</article>

	<article id="7">
		<title>Notes: the most common Git commands</title>
		<createdAt>12/16/2019</createdAt>
		<keywords>git: productivity: </keywords>
		<description></description>
		<src>gitcommands.html</src>
	</article>
</root>
